A Guide to the Fritz Albert Lipmann papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA123
Rockefeller Archive Center
Fritz Albert Lipmann papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1924-1986
Rockefeller Archive Center
Lipmann, Fritz (Fritz Albert)
FA123
56.3 Cubic Feet
Biographical/Historical note
Fritz Albert Lipmann, whose work gave scientists the basis for understanding how cells convert food into energy, was born in Koenigsberg, Germany on June 12, 1899. He earned an M. D. in 1924 and a Ph. D. in chemistry in 1927 at the University of Berlin. He joined Otto Meyerhof's group at the Kaiser Wilhelm Institute, first in Dahlem, then in Heidelberg and in 1930 he associated with Albert Fischer, whom he later followed to the Biological Institute of the Carlsberg Foundation in Copenhagen. Before leaving Germany for Copenhagen he spent the year 1931-1932 as a Rockefeller Foundation Fellow with PA Levene at The Rockefeller University, then known as The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research.
In 1939 Dr. Lipmann came to the United States, to Vincent du Vigneaud's department at the Cornell Medical School. From 1941 until he joined The Rockefeller Institute in 1957, he was associated with the Massachusetts General Hospital and the Harvard Medical School, which in 1949 appointed him professor of biological chemistry. As a biochemist whose primary concern was the transmission, generation, and utilization of cellular energy, he proposed (in 1941) the concept of a metabolic dynamo by which energy-rich phosphate bonds continuously supply the energy needed for the work of building and repairing cells. In 1945 Lipmann isolated Coenzyme A and identified it as a key substance in the biosynthesis of a great variety of cell constituents, including fatty acids, steroids, amino acids, hemoglobin and others. He found that it contained one of the B vitamins, pantothenic acid.
For this discovery of Coenzyme A and its recognition as one of the most important substances in body metabolism, Dr. Lipmann was awarded the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine (along with Hans Kreb) in 1953. Dr. Lipmann moved to The Rockefeller Institute in 1957, becoming Professor Emeritus in 1970. At RU, he worked with charged tRNAs and moved into the field of elongation factors in ribosomal protein synthesis. EFTu and EFTs were discovered at the Rockefeller laboratory.
In 1966 President Johnson presented him with the National Medal of Science, the nation's highest award for scientific achievement, for his original discoveries of molecular mechanisms and his fundamental contributions to the conceptual structure of modern biochemistry. He received numerous other awards, including the Carl Neuberg Medal and the Mead Johnson Award. He was given honorary degrees from the University of Paris, Harvard University, the University of Chicago, the Albert Einstein College of Medicine, Brandeis University, Medizinische Hochschule (Hanover, Germany), the University of Copenhagen, and The Rockefeller University. In 1974, an annual Fritz Lipmann Lecture Series was established at the Max-Planck-Institut für Molekulare Genetik, in Berlin, by the Deutsche Gesellschaft für Biologische Chemie at the behest of his former students and colleagues. In 1975, he received the Orden Pour le mérite für Wissenschaften und Künste from President Walter Scheel of West Germany, in a ceremony held in Bonn. His professional memberships included the National Academy of Sciences, the Deutsche Akademie der Naturforscher Leopoldina in East Germany, a fellow of the Danish Royal Academy of Sciences, the New York Academy of Sciences, and a foreign member of the Royal Society in London.
Dr. Lipmann lectured widely and published numerous scientific articles, publishing at least one article for every year of his professional career, beginning in 1924 up to his death in 1986. He wrote an autobiography The Wanderings of a Biochemist, published by Wiley-Interscience, in 1971. Up until the time of his death, on July 24, 1986, at the age of 87, Dr. Lipmann was actively running a laboratory at The Rockefeller University and conducting research. In the last few years of his life, his research focused on the mechanism of protein synthesis.
Arrangement note
Arranged in chronological and alphabetical order.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 L667
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: personal files, correspondence, lectures, notes, manuscripts, reprints, photographs, slides and audio-visual materials.
Life sciences; Biochemistry; Biology -- Research; Science -- Biological and Medical; Proteins -- Synthesis; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Proteins; Rockefeller University; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- Personal Files, 1924-1986; 1; 1.75 Cubic Feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes award certificates, biographical material, magazines, a medal, telephone/calendar/address books.
  Also includes: scroll from the Israel Biochemical Society; books: In Honoring We Are Honored A Brandeis University tribute to honorary degree recipients 1948-1963, and Roussel Uclaf, from France; Awards: Roswell Park Memorial Institute, 1980; medal, Paris 1979.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged in alphabetical and then in chronological order.
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences Nomination (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - [magazines], 1 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - [magazines], 2 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - [various oversize documents] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Paris Match magazine (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - [oversize photos] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - [large negatives] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lipmann Memorial Concert, 1986; 1 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lipmann Memorial Concert, 1986; 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Lipmann biographical material (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Triangle magazine (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Lipmann Symposium (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - South American trip, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Lipmann laboratory blueprints (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Telephone address book (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - [notebook] (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Degrees (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Giovannella slides (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Obituary materials, 1 of 3 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Obituary materials, 2 of 3 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Obituary materials, 3 of 3 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Pasteur Anniversary (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Calendar/address books, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Calendar/address books, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Calendar/address books, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Calendar/address books, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Calendar/address books, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Calendar/address books, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Calendar/address books, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Calendar/address books, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Calendar/address books, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Calendar/address books, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Calendar/address books, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Calendar/address books, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Calendar/address books, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Calendar/address books, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Calendar/address books, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Calendar/address books, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Calendar/address books, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Calendar/address books, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Calendar/address books, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Calendar/address books, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Calendar/address books, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Calendar/address books, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Calendar/address books, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Calendar/address books, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Calendar/address books, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Calendar/address books, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Calendar/address books, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Scope and Contents
    1984 is not included in the collection.
  - Calendar/address books, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1950-1986; 2; 13.25 Cubic Feet
  Includes both personal and professional correspondence.
  Arranged in chronological and then in alphabetical order.
  - ["A"], 1950s (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Academic Press, 1950s (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - American Society of Biological Chemists, 1950s; 1 of 3 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - American Society of Biological Chemists, 1950s; 2 of 3 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - American Society of Biological Chemists, 1950s; 3 of 3 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Archives of Biochemistry and Biophysics (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - ["B"], 1950s; 1 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - ["B"], 1950s; 2 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Baddiley, Dr. J. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Bronk, Dr. Detlev (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - ["C"], 1950s; 1 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - ["C"], 1950s; 2 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Committee on Non-clinical Investigators (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - ["D"], 1950s (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Dean Clark (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - ["E"], 1950s (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - ["F"], 1950s (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Furio D'Abramo (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - ["G"], 1950s (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - G. D. Novelli (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Gregory, J. D. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Geller, David M. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Gordon Conference (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - ["H"], 1950s; 1 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - ["H"], 1950s; 2 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Hotels (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - ["I"], 1950s (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Israel material (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Interscience Publishers (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - ["J"], 1950s (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - J. D. Judah Fellowship (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Jones, Mary Ellen-Fellowship (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Journal of the American Chemical Society (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - ["K"], 1950s; 1 of 2 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - ["K"], 1950s; 2 of 2 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - ["L"], 1950s; 1 of 2 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - ["L"], 1950s; 2 of 2 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - ["M"], 1950s; 1 of 2 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - ["M"], 1950s; 2 of 2 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Mager-Magnes Scholarship (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - ["N"], 1950s (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - National Academy of Sciences (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Nobel letters (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Nose, Yoshitsugu (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Nozaki (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - ["O"], 1950s (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Ottawa (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - ["P"], 1950s; 1 of 2 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - ["P"], 1950s; 2 of 2 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Peck, Harry D. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Pound Bill (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - ["Q"], 1950s (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Rabinowitz, Murray (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Rhode Island Symposium (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Robbins, Phillips W. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Rockefeller Institute (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - ["S"], 1950s; 1 of 2 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - ["S"], 1950s; 2 of 2 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Sharon, Nathan (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Szilard, P. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - ["T"], 1950s (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Tax information (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Travel expense sheets (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Travel information (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - ["U"], 1950s (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - ["V"], 1950s (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Vogue magazine material (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - ["W"], 1950s; 1 of 2 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - ["W"], 1950s; 2 of 2 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Weber, H. H. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Weiss, Samuel (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - ["X-Y-Z"] (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - ["A"], 1957-1960 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Acs, George (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - American Society of Biological Chemists (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Archives of Biochemistry and Biophysics (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - ["B"], 1957-1960; 1 of 2 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - ["B"], 1957-1960; 2 of 2 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Bates, Harold M. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Brandeis University (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Brode, Dr. Wallace R. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - ["C"], 1957-1960; 1 of 2 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - ["C"], 1957-1960; 2 of 2 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Cahn, Max L. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Calif. visit (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Christmas cards (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - ["D"], 1957-1960 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Delbruck, Axel (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Democratic Advisory Committee (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - ["E"], 1957-1960 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - European Chemists (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - ["F"], 1957-1960 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Federation meetings (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - ["G"], 1957-1960; 1 of 2 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - ["G"], 1957-1960; 2 of 2 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Gunther vs. Ehrenstein (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - ["H"], 1957-1960; 1 of 2 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - ["H"], 1957-1960; 1 of 2 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Hartmann, Guido (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Hasegawa, Eiichi (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Hulsmann, W. C. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - ["I"], 1957-1960 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - ["J"], 1957-1960 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Japanese Biochemical Society (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - ["K"], 1957-1960; 1 of 2 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - ["K"], 1957-1960; 2 of 2 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Kaplan (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Khorana, H. G. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - ["L"], 1957-1960 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Lane (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - ["M"], 1957-1960; 1 of 2 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - ["M"], 1957-1960; 2 of 2 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - McCorquodale & Shapira (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Meyer, Karl (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Monro, Robin (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - ["N"], 1957-1960 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Netherlands Symposium (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - New York Academy meeting (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - ["O"], 1957-1960 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Oak Ridge Symposium (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - ["P"], 1957-1960 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Petrack, Barbara (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - ["R"], 1957-1960 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - ["S"], 1957-1960; 1 of 3 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - ["S"], 1957-1960; 2 of 3 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - ["S"], 1957-1960; 3 of 3 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Szafranski Przemyslaw (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - ["T"], 1957-1960 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Takeda, Masao (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Traut, R. R. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - ["U-V"], 1957-1960 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - ["W"], 1957-1960; 1 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - ["W"], 1957-1960; 2 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - ["X-Y-Z"], 1957-1960 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Zubay, Geoffrey (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - ["A"], 1961-1964; 1 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - ["A"], 1961-1964; 2 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Allende, Jorge E. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - ["B"], 1961-1964; 1 of 3 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - ["B"], 1961-1964; 2 of 3 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - ["B"], 1961-1964; 3 of 3 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Baschang, Gerhard (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Bloemendal, H. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Brandeis University (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - ["C"], 1961-1964 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Chapeville, F. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Conway, Thomas W. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - ["D"], 1961-1964 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - ["E"], 1961-1964 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Ebashi, Setsuro (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Engstrom, Lorentz (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - ["F"], 1961-1964 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - ["G"], 1961-1964; 1 of 2 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - ["G"], 1961-1964; 2 of 2 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Gerlach, Ulrich (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Government inquiry into scientific spending (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - ["H"], 1961-1964; 1 of 2 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - ["H"], 1961-1964; 2 of 2 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Henry, Jean-Charles (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Hierowski, Marian (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - ["I"], 1961-1964 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - ["J"], 1961-1964 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Journal of the American Chemical Society (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - ["K"], 1961-1964; 1 of 2 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - ["K"], 1961-1964; 2 of 2 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Kuncan, Zeljko (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - ["L"], 1961-1964; 1 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - ["L"], 1961-1964; 2 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Langan, Thomas (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - ["M"], 1961-1964; 1 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - ["M"], 1961-1964; 2 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Mano, Yoshitake (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - M-RNA (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - ["N"], 1961-1964; 1 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - ["N"], 1961-1964; 2 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Nathans, Daniel (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Newberg Medal Committee (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - ["O"], 1961-1964 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Ofengand, James (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - ["P"], 1961-1964; 1 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - ["P"], 1961-1964; 2 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - ["R"], 1961-1964; 1 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - ["R"], 1961-1964; 2 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - ["S"], 1961-1964; 1 of 5 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - ["S"], 1961-1964; 2 of 5 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - ["S"], 1961-1964; 3 of 5 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - ["S"], 1961-1964; 4 of 5 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - ["S"], 1961-1964; 5 of 5 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - ["T"], 1961-1964 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - ["U"], 1961-1964 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - ["V"], 1961-1964 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - ["W"], 1961-1964; 1 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - ["W"], 1961-1964; 2 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - ["X-Y-Z"], 1961-1964 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - ["A"], 1965-1968; 1 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - ["A"], 1965-1968; 2 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Applications for laboratory work, 1 of 3 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Applications for laboratory work, 2 of 3 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Applications for laboratory work, 3 of 3 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - ["B"], 1965-1968; 1 of 3 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - ["B"], 1965-1968; 2 of 3 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - ["B"], 1965-1968; 3 of 3 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Bennett, Peter (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Biochemistry (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Biochemistry manuscript review (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Biography (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Brandeis University (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - ["C"], 1965-1968; 1 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - ["C"], 1965-1968; 2 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Chemical Sciences Committee (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Chile correspondence (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Clark, John M., Jr. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Coenzyme A article (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Cold Spring Harbor Symposium (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - ["D"], 1965-1968 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Biography (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Brandeis University (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - ["C"], 1965-1968; 1 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - ["C"], 1965-1968; 2 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Chemical Sciences Committee (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Chile correspondence (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Clark, John M., Jr. (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Coenzyme A article (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Cold Spring Harbor Symposium (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - ["D"], 1965-1968 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - ["E"], 1965-1968 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - ["F"], 1965-1968 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Committee on Organic and Biochemistry, 1 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Committee on Organic and Biochemistry, 2 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Federation meeting, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Federation meeting, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Felicetti, Luciano (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Fleissner, Erwin (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - ["G"], 1965-1968; 1 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - ["G"], 1965-1968; 2 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - German visit (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Gordon conference, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Gordon conference, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Gottesman, Max (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - ["H"], 1965-1968; 1 of 3 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - ["H"], 1965-1968; 2 of 3 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - ["H"], 1965-1968; 3 of 3 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Hadjiolov, A. A. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Hebrew University (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Honors, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - ["I"], 1965-1968 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Ilan, Joseph (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Information Exchange Group (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Israel, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - ["J"], 1965-1968 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Job opportunities (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - ["K"], 1965-1968 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - ["L"], 1965-1968; 1 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - ["L"], 1965-1968; 2 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Laskin Award (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Lectures committee (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Lindau meeting (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - ["M"], 1965-1968; 1 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - ["M"], 1965-1968; 2 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - McClean Hospital Scientific Advisory Committee, 1 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - McClean Hospital Scientific Advisory Committee, 2 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Marchis-Moucen, Guy (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Moroz, Leonard (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - ["N"], 1965-1968 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Nakamoto, Tokumasa (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Naples and Germany (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - National Medal of Science (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Nishizuka, Yasutomi (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - ["O"], 1965-1968 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Orrego, Fernando (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - ["P"], 1965-1968 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Pathology conference, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - ["Q"], 1965-1968 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - ["R"], 1965-1968 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - ["S"], 1965-1968; 1 of 2 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - ["S"], 1965-1968; 2 of 2 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Scher, William (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Seventh International Congress of Biochemistry (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - ["T"], 1965-1968 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - ["U"], 1965-1968 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Ureta, Tito (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - ["V"], 1965-1968 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - ["W"], 1965-1968; 1 of 2 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - ["W"], 1965-1968; 2 of 2 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Wakabayashi, Kazuhiko (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Yu, Chuan-Tao (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - ["X-Y-Z"], 1965-1968 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - ["A"], 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Applications for laboratory work (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - ["B"], 1969-1970; 1 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - ["B"], 1969-1970; 2 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Biochemistry, 1 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Biochemistry, 2 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Brazil letters (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - ["C"], 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Cold Spring Harbor Symposium (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Cooper, David (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Copenhagen, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - ["D"], 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - ["E"], 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Eighth International Congress on Biochemistry, 1 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Eighth International Congress on Biochemistry, 2 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - ["F"], 1969-1970; 1 of 2 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - ["F"], 1969-1970; 2 of 2 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Family of Man Awards (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - FEBS meeting (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Federal support of science (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Fox, J. Lawrence (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - France (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - ["G"], 1969-1970 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Ganoza, M. Clelia (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Germany, 1969 July (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Gevers, Wieland (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Gold, Lawrence (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - ["H"], 1969-1970; 1 of 2 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - ["H"], 1969-1970; 2 of 2 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Haenni, Ann-Lise (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Herrlich, Peter (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Hirsh, David (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Huberman, Alberto (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - ["I"], 1969-1970 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - ["J"], 1969-1970 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - ["K"], 1969-1970; 1 of 2 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - ["K"], 1969-1970; 2 of 2 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Kamer, Martin (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Kaplan, N. O. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Khorana, H. G. (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Krisko, Istvan (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - ["L"], 1969-1970; 1 of 2 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - ["L"], 1969-1970; 2 of 2 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Lasker Award (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Lenard, Jean L. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Lundsgaard letters (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - ["M"], 1969-1970; 1 of 2 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - ["M"], 1969-1970; 2 of 2 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Malken, Martin (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Meyerhof Symposium (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - [Madrid Conference] (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Molecular biology (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - ["N"], 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - ["O"], 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Oak Ridge Laboratories (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Personal (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - ["Q"], 1969-1970 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - ["R"], 1969-1970 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Reboud, Jean Paul (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Rockefeller University Senate (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Royal Society (Box 29, Folder 6)